<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RizPur</title>
    <link>https://rizpur.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RizPur</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rizpur.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Huricane Melissa, Disaster Relief</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/rebuild-ja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/rebuild-ja/</guid>
      <description>After Hurricane Melissa, Brian messaged me on Instagram. He sells me a vision from his friend on a solution. I message them back on Whatsapp.&#xA;The Problem Jamaica moves slow. We&amp;rsquo;re reactive.&#xA;When disasters hit, we respond. We scramble. We do our best with incomplete information. Communities that are popular on IG and TikTok get help. Rural communities get forgotten.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s not because Jamaicans don&amp;rsquo;t care. It&amp;rsquo;s because we lack coordination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between Yam, Baguette, and Noodles</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/blogs/between-yam-baguette-and-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/blogs/between-yam-baguette-and-noodles/</guid>
      <description>🍂 The Taoist Horse Story A farmer&amp;rsquo;s horse runs away.&#xA;The neighbours say, &amp;ldquo;Bredda, dat wicked, a wah kinda crosses dat?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer says, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The next day the horse comes back with four wild horses.&#xA;The neighbours say, &amp;ldquo;Yow boss, blessings a rain pon yuh! Yuh lucky bad man!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer says, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer&amp;rsquo;s son tries to ride one of the wild horses and breaks his leg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somnia: AI meets Dreams</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/somnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/somnia/</guid>
      <description>The ancient Greeks believed dreams were messages from the gods. Freud called them &amp;ldquo;the royal road to the unconscious.&amp;rdquo; Modern neuroscience sees them as the brain&amp;rsquo;s way of processing, consolidating, making sense of chaos.&#xA;But here&amp;rsquo;s what fascinates me: dreams are data. Patterns waiting to be found. Your subconscious speaks to you every night in symbols, emotions, recurring themes—and most of us never learn to listen.&#xA;What if we could analyze dreams the same way we analyze data?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caribbean Log Tracker</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/caribbean-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/caribbean-tracker/</guid>
      <description>A Real-Time Data Management Solution Ever thought about how to make sense of all the data you have just floating around your business? This application, Caribbean Log Data Dashboard, built with React Leaflet, MySQL, and Laravel aims to address that.&#xA;Dashboard Architecture React Leaflet: For the cool interactive map you see on the dashboard. MySQL: Where all the data lives. Laravel: Makes sure everything talks to each other nicely and keeps it secure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eye-Tracking AAC System</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/eyetracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/eyetracker/</guid>
      <description>Augmentative and Alternative Communication (AAC) refers to the field of tech that utilizes communication systems to aide or supplement speech or writing for those with impairments or difficulties communicating.&#xA;It allows people to regain or enhance certain communications skills usually impaired by congenital conditions or acquired maladies such as autism or cerebral palsy.&#xA;Inspiration I was captivated by a particular episode of Breaking Bad where Hector Salamanca, a paraplegic and mute character, is being questioned by the DEA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of Jamaica</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/blogs/jamaica-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/blogs/jamaica-history/</guid>
      <description>In 2021, amid global challenges, I taught English in France to young minds from kindergarten (CP) to grade 5 (CM2). Their curiosity about Jamaica sparked an enchanting video project.&#xA;Join this post to delve into our journey during unprecedented times. Through a crafted video, we embarked on a virtual exploration of Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s historical richness, culture, and heartwarming cross-border connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eTrustWallet: The Idea to End Divorce Forever</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/ewallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/ewallet/</guid>
      <description>2020-2021. COVID lockdowns. Bitcoin at $60k. Stimulus checks hitting accounts. Everyone suddenly understood &amp;ldquo;decentralized finance.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;I was deep in it—ETH, ADA, BTC, and way too many shitcoins. NFTs were the future. Smart contracts were going to change everything. And I had the idea: an immutable trust wallet that would end corruption, prevent government embezzlement, and somehow solve divorces.&#xA;I was 22 and very confident.&#xA;The Concept Build a smart contract where:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
