<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamaica on RizPur</title>
    <link>https://rizpur.com/tags/jamaica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamaica on RizPur</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rizpur.com/tags/jamaica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Huricane Melissa, Disaster Relief</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/rebuild-ja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/rebuild-ja/</guid>
      <description>After Hurricane Melissa, Brian messaged me on Instagram. He sells me a vision his friend Travis has, on a solution. I message them back on Whatsapp.&#xA;What started as a conversation between three people quickly became something bigger. Old university friends. Current friends. Good friends. New friends. The team formed organically—people who believed Jamaica deserved better disaster response infrastructure. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t just Brian and Travis. It was us. All of us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between Yam, Baguette, and Noodles</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/blogs/between-yam-baguette-and-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/blogs/between-yam-baguette-and-noodles/</guid>
      <description>🍂 The Taoist Horse Story A farmer&amp;rsquo;s horse runs away.&#xA;The neighbours say, &amp;ldquo;Bredda, dat wicked, a wah kinda crosses dat?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer says, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The next day the horse comes back with four wild horses.&#xA;The neighbours say, &amp;ldquo;Yow boss, blessings a rain pon yuh! Yuh lucky bad man!&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer says, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The farmer&amp;rsquo;s son tries to ride one of the wild horses and breaks his leg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caribbean Log Tracker</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/projects/caribbean-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/projects/caribbean-tracker/</guid>
      <description>A Real-Time Data Management Solution Ever thought about how to make sense of all the data you have just floating around your business? This application, Caribbean Log Data Dashboard, built with React Leaflet, MySQL, and Laravel aims to address that.&#xA;Dashboard Architecture React Leaflet: For the cool interactive map you see on the dashboard. MySQL: Where all the data lives. Laravel: Makes sure everything talks to each other nicely and keeps it secure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of Jamaica</title>
      <link>https://rizpur.com/blogs/jamaica-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rizpur.com/blogs/jamaica-history/</guid>
      <description>In 2021, amid global challenges, I taught English in France to young minds from kindergarten (CP) to grade 5 (CM2). Their curiosity about Jamaica sparked an enchanting video project.&#xA;Join this post to delve into our journey during unprecedented times. Through a crafted video, we embarked on a virtual exploration of Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s historical richness, culture, and heartwarming cross-border connections.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
